ILGWU. Local 105 photographs 5780/053 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU. Local 105 photographs
1938-1968
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Local 105
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/053 P
0.67 cubic feet
0.67 linear ft.
Photographs.
This collection consists of photographs documenting Local 105's activities between 1938 and 1968.
6717818
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 31, 2012
EAD encoding:
Kathryn Dowgiewicz, June 10, 2014
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States, the ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. In 1995, the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) to form the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE).
Biographical / Historical
Local 105, International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), also known as the Snowsuits, Ski Wear, Leggings, Infants and Novelty Sportswear Union, was based in New York City. It represented workers employed in various specialty garment shops in the New York area.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains photographs that help to document the activities of Local 105 from 1938 to 1968. The images show the members and leaders of Local 105 through portraits and group photographs, at activities and events such as dinners and luncheons hosted in honor of the guests of Local 105, and at rallies.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/053: ILGWU. Local 105 records 5780/053 AV: ILGWU. Local 105 audio recordings
Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State); International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 105 (New York, N.Y.)
6717818
- Picture 1, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes David Dubinsky, Ethel Kennedy, Robert Wagner, and Martin L. Cohen; coincides with race for New York Senate by Robert F. Kennedy; October 1964
- Picture 2. ILGWU Dinner (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Dinner honoring New York City Mayor John V. Lindsday; includes Martin L. Cohen and John V. Lindsay; circa lates 1960s
- Picture 3. ILGWU retiring sewing machine after 1 millionth stitch (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Includes Harriet L. Cohen, Mrs. Meany, David Dubinsky, George Meany, Martin L. Cohen; 20th Anniversary, Local 105
- Picture 4. Labor Day Parade (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Includes David Dubinsky, Robert Wagner, Grand Marshall George Meany, Mrs. Meany, Martin L. Cohen; early 1960s
- Picture 5. ILGWU Presidential Rally in 1968 for Hubert H. Humphrey (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Includes Alan King, Shirley Winters, Martin L. Cohen
- Picture 6. Local 105 Manager-Secretary Martin L. Cohen (Box 1, Folder 6)
  At offices of Local 105 at 575 8th Avenue in Manhattan, circa late 1960s
- Picture 7. ILGWU Dinner (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Includes Martin Cohen, Harriet Cohen, Louis Stulberg, and Mrs. Stulberg; circa mid 1960s
- Picture 8. ILGWU members give gift of Patek Phillips watch to Manager-Secretary Martin L. Cohen (Box 1, Folder 8)
  circa early 1950s
- Picture 9. ILGWU Local 105 members give first of two portrait gifts to Manager-Secretary Martin L. Cohen (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Includes Assistant Manager-Secretary Henry Prastein; circa mid-1950s
- Picture 10. ILGWU Local 105 members give second gift portrait to Manager Secretary Martin L. Cohen (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Portrait by Henry S. Moskowitz; includes Amy Best Merchant
- Picture 11. Group photograph, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Luncheon meeting tendered in honor of the officers of the Jewis Consumptives' Relief Society of Denter, Colorado by the leaders of the Trade Unions of New York; Hotel Astor, New York; March 30, 1938
- Picture 12. ILGWU Dinner (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Diner honoring New York City Mayor Abraham D. Beam; indlues Sol Chaikin, Mrs. Chaikin, Harriet Cohen, Martin Cohen, Abraham Beame, Mary Beame, Hayward Hale Braine, and Mrs. Braine; circa late 1970s
- Picture 13. Companion picture to #10 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Presentation of second portrait by members of Local 105 to Manager-Secretary Martin Cohen
- Picture 14. ILGWU Dinner (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Dinner for Mayor Abraham D. Beame; indcludes Abraham Beame and Martin L. Cohen; circa early 1970s
- Picture 15. Meany Presentation (Box 1, Folder 15)
  ILGWU presrentation to AFL-CIO President George Meany; includes George Meany, Martin Cohen; circa mid-1970s
- Picture 16. FDR Rally, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Local 105 rally to elect FDC; includes Jacob Heller and Martin L. Cohen
- Picture 17. ILGWU Unity House Weekend (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Includes Martin L. Cohen and Rebecca Cohen; circa early 1940s
- Picture 18. First officers of Local 105, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Inclues Assistant Manager Martin L. Cohen, Manager Jacob Heller, and unidentified man
- Picture 19. Local 105 Aids British Labor (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Includes Jacob Heller, Martin L. Cohen, Mrs. Heller, Tuprow, and Henry Prastein; circa 1941-1942
- Picture 20. ILGWU Local 105 luncheon with leadership and business agents, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Includes Jacob Heller and Martin L. Cohen
- Picture 21. Martin L. Cohen gives refugee check (Box 1, Folder 21)
  circa 1948-1949
- Picture 22. First Executive Board, Local 105 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  Includes Martin L. Cohen, Jacob Heller, Henry Prastein, and Morris Bagnow
- Picture 23. Martin L. Cohen becomes second manager of Local 105; picture 24, ILGWU presentation; and 25, Finance Committee (Box 1, Folder 23)
  Includes Henry Prastein, Martin L. Cohen, Amy Best Merchant, Harriet L. Cohen, Jacob Heller; 1948, mid-1960s, and late 1930s